Nelly-Charlott Schneider, Frontend Developer

Berlin, +49 17656816398, nellychschneider@gmail.com

LinkedIn, GitHub, Personal website

I am a Intermediate Frontend Web Developer with almost three years of experience working with React, React Native and TypeScript. Equipped with a diverse and promising skill-set and ready to acquire new skills, I am able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate in a team setting.

SKILLS

React. React Native, TypeScript, GraphQL, JavaScript, HTML & CSS, Git & GitHub

WORK EXPERIENCE

November 2019 - Present

Intermediate Software Engineer at Nuri (ex Bitwala), Berlin

- Implemented and updated application modules under the direction of Senior Software Developers.
- Effectively coded software changes and alterations based on specific design specifications.
- Working with agile methodologies

April 2022 – May 2022

Frontend Developer at KasparAI, Copenhagen

• Transitioning their Vanilla JavaScript website to ReactJS

EDUCATION

August 2019 – October 2019

Ironhack, Berlin 9-Week Web Development Bootcamp

Acquired Skills:

- HTML5, CSS3 & Design Responsive Web Design
- Fundamentals of Object-oriented programming based on JavaScript
- Integration of third party services (APIs)
- Writing clean, modular and efficient code and develop well-tested applications using TDD (Test Driven Development) principles
- Agile tools and methodologies

HOBBIES

I love being outdoors and being creative. Playing guitar, some banjo and bass, singing, making (sometimes digital) art and video montages of trips.

Recently I started having an interest in VR and the many possibilities of it, so I'm trying to learn more about this technology.

LANGUAGES

German, Native speaker

English, Highly proficient